CHE NSOH BLANCHARD

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

che.blancoo58@gmail.com| GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with over 2 years of professional experience working on personal projects and one year of experience as a freelancer. Self-motivated, fast learner who is passionate about providing software or solutions that can improve Man's productivity and reduce labor.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3 Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Python, Django

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

Sep 2020 - Present

Tic-tac-toe Game — A game built using Object-oriented principles played by 2 users who exchange turns. This game is used to relieve depression.

Built with: Ruby, Rspec

Appointment-V1 — MVP appointment web app to sign up or log in and book an appointment with a favorite doctor or specialist. App seeks to cut off or drastically reduce waiting time due to registration for consultation in hospitals

Built with: HTML/CSS3, Bootstrap, Ruby, Rails(API), Rspec, React and Redux. (appointment)

Manage school— An application for registering students, filling their marks, viewing students' marks, and downloading their results. The app helps to drastically reduce time spent on filling users' marks manually and reduce errors in mark calculations.

Built with: Pyhton, Django, HTML/CSS, Bootsrap (<u>Live Demo</u>)

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

May 2021 - July 2021

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.
- Code reviewer

Aproplat

Remote, Remote

Full-stack engineer back-end intensive

sep, 2021 - Present

- Implemented a multitenant system using Rails API that enables several subdomains and domains to use one platform
- Perform analysis and design and implementation of a school and thesis management systems
- Integrate one-time payment and subscriptions with stripe on an API web App
- Perform code reviews for other junior developers

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

Sep 2020 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to

communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

UNIVERSITY NAME

THE UNIVERSITY OF BUEA

Bachelors in Computer Science

Sep 2014 – Feb 2017

Relevant coursework included: Data structure and algorithms, C/C++ programming language and logic programming, Java programming language, and database design, Information systems, Compiler design, Complexity of algorithms, Networking, and Software engineering.